A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Cultural Interests, Series E FA314
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Museums
  - Museums - American Museum of Natural History - Planetarium, 1929-1933 (Box 14, Folder 148)
    Printed material on invention of apparatus and the first U.S. planetariums. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. declined to help Museum buy one; eventually Charles Hayden gift made purchase possible. John D. Rockefeller 3rd was a member of Museum's Planetarium Authority. Tentative plans for putting planetarium in Rockefeller Center. Norman Bel Geddes' report on Planetarium. Correspondents include F. Fieseler, F. T. Davison, Henry Osborne, Thomas B. Appleget, Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Museums - American Museum of Natural History - Planetarium, 1934-1945 (Box 14, Folder 149)
  - Museums - American Museum of Natural History - David Rockefeller, 1938-1961 (Box 14, Folder 150)
    David Rockefeller contributions for purchase of beetle collections and to pay salary of beetle specialist. Sets up Rockefeller Coleoptera Fund and David Rockefeller Fund. Requests for non-entomological gifts declined; declined to become Trustee. Much discussion of bugs. Correspondents include Mont Cazier, Jerome Rozen, Jr., David Rockefeller, Arthur W. Packard.
    138D
  - Museums - American Museum of Natural History - David Rockefeller - Southwest Research Station, 1953-1956 (Box 14, Folder 151)
    David Rockefeller helps establish and maintain biological laboratory in Arizona. David Rockefeller-Mont Cazier correspondence about Station's progress and their mutual beetle collections. David Rockefeller designated Benefactor of Museum. Printed material and photos. Correspondents include David Rockefeller, Mont Cazier, Detlev Bronk, Willis Gertsch.
  - Museums - American Museum of Natural History - David Rockefeller - Southwest Research Station, 1957-1961 (Box 14, Folder 152)
  - Museums - American Museum of Natural History - David Rockefeller - Southwest Research Station, 1957-1961 (Box 14, Folder 0152A)
  - Museums - American Museum of Natural History - Laurance S. Rockefeller, 1936-1961 (Box 15, Folder 153)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller a Life Member and Associate Benefactor. Laurance S. Rockefeller and Mary French Rockefeller annual contributors. Consideration of Leonard Outhwaite for Museum post. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, Leonard Outhwaite.
    138L
    Open per DA, 06/13/2008.
  - Museums - American Museum of Natural History - Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1936-1954 (Box 15, Folder 154)
    Nelson A. Rockefeller an Associate Member; loans of Peruvian textiles; gifts of Peruvian mummy bundles and primitive art. In 1952, $1,000 nonrecurring contribution. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, F. T. Davison.
    138N
  - Museums - American Museum of Natural History - John D. Rockefeller 3rd, 1933-1937 (Box 15, Folder 155)
    In 1933, John D. Rockefeller 3rd joined Board of Trustees and various committees. Correspondence about museum finances, charter revisions, museum work in prisons and schools, personnel changes, the Ten-Year Program, war and post-war problems, various Museum projects and expeditions. 1944 Director's Report; 1947 plans for reducing Museum budget and for modernization. President Parr's addresses on the purpose of a museum; plans for new auditorium; retirement policies. In 1953, John D. Rockefeller 3rd was elected Benefactor; in 1955, he resigned from the Board. Correspondents include F. T. Davison, A. S. Parr, Charles Russell, Burton Turnbull, Robert Moses, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
    138J
  - Museums - American Museum of Natural History - John D. Rockefeller 3rd, 1938-1941 (Box 15, Folder 156)
  - Museums - American Museum of Natural History - John D. Rockefeller 3rd, 1942-1944 (Box 15, Folder 157)
  - Museums - American Museum of Natural History - John D. Rockefeller 3rd, 1945-April 1947 (Box 15, Folder 158)
  - Museums - American Museum of Natural History - John D. Rockefeller 3rd, May 1947-1949 (Box 15, Folder 159)
  - Museums - American Museum of Natural History - John D. Rockefeller 3rd, 1950-1951 (Box 16, Folder 160)
  - Museums - American Museum of Natural History - John D. Rockefeller 3rd, 1952-1957 (Box 16, Folder 161)
  - Museums - American Museum of Natural History - John D. Rockefeller 3rd - Pension Plan, 1934-1950 (Box 16, Folder 162)
  - Museums - American Museum of Natural History - John D. Rockefeller 3rd - Contributions, 1934-1955 (Box 16, Folder 163)
  - Museums - American Museum of Natural History - John D. Rockefeller 3rd - Contributions - Hall of Man Project, 1951-1961 (Box 16, Folder 164)
    Began as attempt to incorporate Health Museum exhibits into American Museum. John D. Rockefeller 3rd gave $95,000 to complete Hall. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s letter to John D. Rockefeller 3rd regarding the gift.
  - Museums - American Museum of Natural History - John D. Rockefeller 3rd - Nominating Committee, 1946-1949 (Box 16, Folder 165)
    John D. Rockefeller 3rd a member; correspondence regarding nominations for Management Board, Museum Board, etc. Correspondents include W. D. Burden, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Museums - American Museum of Natural History - John D. Rockefeller 3rd - Nominating Committee, 1950-1954 (Box 16, Folder 166)
  - Museums - American Museum of Natural History - Reports and Surveys, 1922, 1927 (Box 16, Folder 167)
    "Report on the American Museum of Natural History, 1922," prepared by Dr. Beardsley Ruml (61 pp.)."The American Museum of Natural History Report, August 1927," prepared by Thomas B. Appleget (95 pp.).
    138J or 138
  - Museums - American Museum of Natural History - Reports and Surveys, 1940-1941, 1951 (Box 17, Folder 168)
    "Preliminary Report of the Secretary of the Trustees' Committee on the Coordination of Exhibits," prepared by George C. Vaillant, April 8, 1941."Note on Questions of Space and Subject Matter Involved in the Incorporation of the American Museum of Public Health into the Program of Exhibits on Man under Consideration by the American Museum of Natural History"."Proposed Treatment by American Museum of Natural History of Biological and Health Exhibits Now Owned by the American Museum of Public Health," December 11, 1941."A Study of the American Museum of Natural History Made for the Board of Trustees by Alexander G. Ruthven, 1941" (42 pp.)."The American Museum of Natural History Preliminary Survey of Organization and Management Practices," prepared by Cresap, McCormick and Paget, 1951.
  - Museums - Museum of the City of New York, 1923-1929 (Box 17, Folder 169)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributions to Museum, gift of rooms from John D. Rockefellers 4 W. 54th Street home, and Lucy Aldrich dresses. Change in Museum; new building. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    138.1
  - Museums - Museum of the City of New York, 1930-1961 (Box 17, Folder 170)
  - Museums - Museum of the City of New York - Pledge, April 26, 1927, 1927-1929 (Box 17, Folder 171)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $450,000 toward cost of new building.
  - Museums - Laboratory of Anthropology, 1926-January 1928 (Box 17, Folder 172)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributions to pre-opening expenses; election of Jesse Nusbaum as director. Nelson A. Rockefeller a participating member. Gifts to Museum; Museum studies; consolidation with School of American Research and State Museum of New Mexico. Tributes to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas B. Appleget, Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, Nelson A. Rockefeller, H. C. Bumpus, Jesse Nusbaum, Horace Albright.
    138.2
  - Museums - Laboratory of Anthropology, February 1928-1931 (Box 17, Folder 173)
  - Museums - Laboratory of Anthropology, 1932-1933 (Box 17, Folder 174)
  - Museums - Laboratory of Anthropology, 1934-1941 (Box 18, Folder 175)
  - Museums - Laboratory of Anthropology, 1942-1946 (Box 18, Folder 176)
  - Museums - Laboratory of Anthropology, 1947-1957 (Box 18, Folder 177)
  - Museums - Laboratory of Anthropology, 1958 (Box 18, Folder 178)
  - Museums - Laboratory of Anthropology, 1959-1961 (Box 18, Folder 179)
  - Museums - Laboratory of Anthropology - Navajo Indian Survey, 1932-1934 (Box 18, Folder 180)
    Emergency relief needs of Navajos; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. purchased silver art work from Navajos, gave it to Museum.
  - Museums - Laboratory of Anthropology - Pueblo Indian Pottery, 1932-1937 (Box 18, Folder 181)
    Publication of volume by Kenneth Chapman.
  - Museums - Laboratory of Anthropology - Contributions, 1927-1959 (Box 18, Folder 182)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. annual contributions for maintenance and building fund, and for purchase of Nagel tract and Indian articles; in 1957, he gave $50,000 toward publication fund. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Thomas B. Appleget, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Kenneth Chapman, Jesse Nusbaum.
  - Museums - Laboratory of Anthropology - Contributions - Pledge, November 13, 1930, 1930-1934 (Box 19, Folder 183)
    Toward director's house.
  - Museums - Laboratory of Anthropology - Contributions - Pledge, 1928, 1928-1935 (Box 19, Folder 184)
    For maintenance of laboratory.
  - Museums - Laboratory of Anthropology - Contributions - Pledge Amendment, January 10, 1933, 1932-1934 (Box 19, Folder 185)
    Modification of 1928 pledge.
  - Museums - Sante Fe - Indian Arts Fund, 1926-1938 (Box 19, Folder 186)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributions toward purchase of Indian pottery, Mexican furniture, and Indian blankets. List of items purchased. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Kenneth Chapman.
    138.21
  - Museums - Sante Fe - Indian Arts Fund - Kenneth Chapmans Reports, 1928-1931 (Box 19, Folder 187)
    Reports on expenditure of John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s pledge for purchases.
  - Museums - Museum of Navajo Ceremonial Art, 1940-1961 (Box 19, Folder 188)
    In 1940, Abby Aldrich Rockefeller and Nelson A. Rockefeller became members; no real family interest however. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, Dana S. Creel.
    138.23
  - Museums - Miscellaneous, 1928-1952 (Box 19, Folder 189)
    Most appeals from various museums declined; some one-time contributions. Abby Aldrich Rockefeller membership in Virginia Fine Arts Museum; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. interest in Shelburne, Vt. Carriage Museum; Dr. Valentiner's recollections of Abby Aldrich Rockefeller as art patron. Correspondents include Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Montgomery Bradley.
    138.3
  - Museums - Miscellaneous, 1953-1957 (Box 19, Folder 190)
  - Museums - Miscellaneous, 1953-1957 (Box 19, Folder 0190A)
  - Museums - Miscellaneous, 1958-1961 (Box 19, Folder 191)
  - Museums - Miscellaneous, 1958-1961 (Box 19, Folder 0191A)
  - Museums - Miscellaneous - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1946-1961 (Box 20, Folder 192)
    Family memberships in Museum; relations between it and Museum of Modern Art.
  - Museums - Miscellaneous - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1946-1961 (Box 20, Folder 0192A)
  - Museums - Pennsylvania Museum of Art, 1928-1960 (Box 20, Folder 193)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. a Benefactor; Nelson A. Rockefeller contributions; gift of Franklin portraits by Abby Aldrich Rockefeller. Museum activities. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, F. Kimball.
    138.4
  - Museums - Pennsylvania Museum of Art - Clarke Collection of American Portraits, 1928-1931 (Box 20, Folder 194)
    Catalog. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s interest in Benjamin West portrait.
  - Museums - Pennsylvania Museum of Art - Bigot Model of Rome, 1927-1934 (Box 20, Folder 195)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gift toward purchase of model.
  - Museums - Museum of Science and Industry, 1925-1949 (Box 20, Folder 196)
    Charter, articles of incorporation, by-laws. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. a Patron; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Nelson A. Rockefeller contributing memberships. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Thomas B. Appleget, Nelson A. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    138.5
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art, 1929-1933 (Box 20, Folder 197)
    Exhibit of paintings; lease of property; policies. Marble bust of John D. Rockefeller by J. Davidson. Exhibit of Soviet frescoes; industrial art show. Nelson A. Rockefeller's purchase of Ahron Ben-Schmuel's "Pugilist." Relations with Metropolitan Museum. Gift of Abby Aldrich Rockefeller prints; loans of family-owned art; additions to Museum; changes in personnel; special exhibitions. Correspondents include Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Charles O. Heydt, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Conger Goodyear.
    138.6
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art, 1934-1941 (Box 20, Folder 198)
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art, 1942-1951 (Box 20, Folder 199)
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art, 1952-1958 (Box 20, Folder 200)
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art, 1959-1962 (Box 21, Folder 201)
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Sculpture Garden, 1951-1953 (Box 21, Folder 202)
    Nelson A. Rockefeller contributes cost of garden.
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Sculpture Garden, 1951-1953 (Box 21, Folder 0202A)
    David Rockefeller contributes cost of garden.
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Entertainment of Servicemen, 1942-1944 (Box 21, Folder 203)
    Family contributions to expenses.
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Japanese House Exhibition, 1952-1958 (Box 21, Folder 204)
    John D. Rockefeller 3rd underwrites construction of house in Museum garden; successful showing; other exhibitions of house.
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Lease, 23 West 53rd Street, 1940-1944 (Box 21, Folder 205)
    Lease of space for Museum storage.
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Lease, 680 5th Avenue, 1940-1942 (Box 21, Folder 206)
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Use of Vault of Pocantico Hills, 1951-1961 (Box 21, Folder 207)
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller, 1959-1961 (Box 21, Folder 208)
    Open per DHS 02/16/2001.
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Endowment Fund, 1934-1935 (Box 21, Folder 209)
    John D. Rockefeller 3rd pledge; Nelson A. Rockefeller membership on Finance Committee; investment program. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Cornelius Bliss.
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Finances, 1941-1949 (Box 21, Folder 210)
    Budget contributions. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, Arthur W. Packard, I. Ulrich.
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Junior Advisory Committee, 1931-1932 (Box 21, Folder 211)
    Work of Committee; Nelson A. Rockefeller pledge to Museum. 1932 mural exhibition; selection and loan of paintings. Objections to Sacco-Vanzetti picture exhibition. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, Nelson A. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Alfred Barr, Conger Goodyear.
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Contributions to Budget, 1946-1962 (Box 21, Folder 212)
    General and special contributions by John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Abby Rockefeller Mauze, and other family members. 1959 summary of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributions. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Abby Rockefeller Mauze, R. C. Bates.
    138.61
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Contributions to Budget - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. 1960 Gift (Box 21, Folder 213)
    $1,000,000 toward 30th anniversary drive.
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Contributions to Budget - Laurance S. Rockefeller and Mary French Rockefeller, 1939-1961 (Box 21, Folder 214)
    Contributions for general and special purposes.
    Open per MAQ 09/27/2004.
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Contributions to Budget - John D. Rockefeller 3rd 1960 Pledge, 1960-1961 (Box 21, Folder 215)
    $250,000 in securities toward thirtieth anniversary drive.
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - David Rockefeller Contributions, 1946-1956 (Box 21, Folder 216)
    David Rockefeller contributions to budget and for special purposes. Correspondents include David Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Dana S. Creel, Richard Dana.
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - David Rockefeller Contributions, 1957-1959 (Box 21, Folder 217)
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - David Rockefeller Contributions, 1960-1961 (Box 22, Folder 218)
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Contributions, 1935-1950 (Box 22, Folder 219)
    Abby Aldrich Rockefeller contributions to annual budgets, collection of theatrical material for Dance Archives, Film library, building fund, books for army camps, Veterans' art center, and Print Index. Correspondents include Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller, I. Ulrich, John Abbott.
    138.61B
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Contributions - December 1937 Purchasing Fund, 1937-1939 (Box 22, Folder 220)
    Creation, purposes, contributions.
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Contributions - September 1933 Pledge, 1933-1934 (Box 22, Folder 221)
    Abby Aldrich Rockefeller conditional pledge.
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Trustees, 1941-1959 (Box 22, Folder 222)
    Scattered announcements of appointments as trustees. Correspondents include Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller, David Rockefeller.
    138.610B
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Membership Privileges, 1938-1959 (Box 22, Folder 223)
    Descriptions of museum activities; family membership; membership changes resulting from changes in dues. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, David Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Mary French Rockefeller.
    138.614
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Nelson A. Rockefeller Contributions, 1940-1957 (Box 22, Folder 224)
    138.615
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Department of Photography, 1940-1950 (Box 22, Folder 225)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller was a member of the Photographic Committee; catalogs of exhibits. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller.
    138.618
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Miscellaneous Publications, 1940-1950 (Box 22, Folder 226)
    Printed material describing founding of Museum, growth, public service. Catalogs and bulletins. Includes: Painting & Sculpture Collection (1950); Guide to Modern Architecture Northeast States (1940); Murals by American Painters & Photographers (1932); Paul Klee (1941).
    138.619
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Miscellaneous Publications, 1940-1950 (Box 22, Folder 227)
    Printed material describing founding of Museum, growth, public service. Catalogs and bulletins. Includes: Organic Design in Home Furnishings (1941); The War Veterans' Arts Center, 1944-1948; The Year's Work: Annual Report to the Board of Trustees and the Corporation Members of The Museum of Modern Art for the Year June 30, 1939-July 1, 1940; The Year's Work: Annual Report to the Board of Trustees and the Corporation Members of The Museum of Modern Art for the Year July 1, 1940-June 30, 1941; New York Art Calendar, November 1-15, 1941; New York Art Calendar, November 15-December 1, 1941; The Museum of Modern Art, New York; various brochures, pamphlets, and magazine articles.
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Miscellaneous Publications, 1940-1950 (Box 23, Folder 228)
    Printed material describing founding of Museum, growth, public service. Board report, "The Museum of Modern Art, New York," ca. 1937.
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Miscellaneous Publications, 1940-1950 (Box 23, Folder 229)
    Printed material describing founding of Museum, growth, public service. Catalogs and bulletins. Includes: The Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Print Room: Master Prints from the Museum Collection, 1949; various editions of The Bulletin of the Museum of Modern Art, 1940-1944; New York Art Calendar, October 15-November 1, 1941.
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Annual Reports - Director, 1940-1958 (Box 23, Folder 230)
    Comments on Museum operations; printed reports. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard.
    138.620
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Arthur Jones Survey, 1946 (Box 23, Folder 231)
    Plans for survey; review of organization; recommended changes.
    138.621
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - 1947 Building Campaign (Box 23, Folder 232)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller pledge to building and Program Fund. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller.
    138.622
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Contributions, 1949-1952 (Box 23, Folder 233)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr., although not personally interested in modern art, was the largest single contributor to the Museum up to 1949. Gifts in land and securities. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Philip Keebler.
    138.623
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Contributions - Gift of 54th Street Frontage, 1937-1944 (Box 23, Folder 234)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave Museum 10-16 West 57th Street for its garden, 1937.
    138.63
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - New Building - Property Transfers, 1936-1946 (Box 23, Folder 235)
    Exchange and sale of properties on W. 53rd St. by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to Museum; cancellation of restrictions on property. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - New Building - Property Transfers - Property Purchase and Transfer, 1936 (Box 23, Folder 236)
    Nelson A. Rockefeller-Abby Aldrich Rockefeller agreement to purchase property if museum unable to raise funds for construction.
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - New Building, 1936-1943 (Box 23, Folder 237)
    Purchase of property; repairs. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller.
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art -Worlds Fair Sculpture Garden, 1939 (Box 23, Folder 238)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s authorization to alter W. 54th St. property. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Frank Staley.
    138.63A
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art -Worlds Fair Sculpture Garden - Lease, 1939-1944 (Box 23, Folder 239)
    Lease of W. 54th St. property to Museum.
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art -Worlds Fair Sculpture Garden - Wright Exhibition and House, 1940 (Box 23, Folder 240)
    Building of house in garden as tribute to Frank Lloyd Wright.
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Office Building, 1942-1947 (Box 23, Folder 241)
    Work of Museum during war, cataloging and analyzing copyrighted films, combating foreign propaganda. Work with Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.s agreement to give Museum property on south side of West 54th Street for office building. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, Stephen Clark.
    138.63B
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Purchase of 21 West 53rd Street, 1945-1949 (Box 23, Folder 242)
    Nelson A. Rockefeller loan to purchase property; conveyance to Museum. Correspondents include Phillip Keebler, John Abbott.
    138.63C
  - Museums - Museum of Modern Art - Exhibitions, 1939-1955 (Box 23, Folder 243)
    Announcement of exhibitions; receipts for family objects loaned to Museum for exhibition. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Laurance S. Rockefeller.
    138.69
  - Museums - American Association of Museums, 1925-1956 (Box 24, Folder 244)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributions to association; John D. Rockefeller 3rd contribution for study of museums; Dana S. Creel interest in association's work. Correspondents include Kenneth Chorley, Dana S. Creel, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
    138.7